# **Khalil Pratap**

# PERSONAL DETAILS

E-mail	khalilpratap@hotmail.com
Phone	+65 9448 0478
Address	479 Valley Park, 09-04 River Valley Road, 248364 Singapore
	https://www.linkedin.com/in/khalil-pratap-71b89220

# PERSONAL STATEMENT

An energetic, driven and highly motivated professional with 15 years experience who has a strong desire to succeed and who possesses the ability to build positive working relationships with customers. As a highly effective communicator he can quickly gain a grasp of a client's strategic direction and requirements. He is confident that he has the skills, experience and 'can do' attitude to meet your expectations.

# **EXPERIENCE**

# Head of Account Development, Global Client Group, Singapore

February 2017 - Now

American Express International Inc

- a) Leading the Account Management Team in a B2B & T&E environment, prospecting, account managing and closing a variety of key industry opportunities with a commercial card proposition
- b) Driving the growth of the Booked Charge Volume and client retention within the team.
- c) Maintaining scorecard sales success measured through the achievement of team sales growth in terms of new/new volume, carryover and total number of new customers acquired by the team
- d) Creating and developing sales strategies to accelerate the penetration various aspects of billings on the full range of Corporate products
- e) Driving initiatives with merchants that deliver ECV growth in key non-T&E areas by using a strong commercial acumen
- f) Actively participating in the market's leadership team with responsibilities for supporting the broader GCP Singapore business strategies and employee engagement initiatives within the Singapore market
- g) Holding accountability for fully engaging in Performance Management & Developing Planning Process with a clear focus on employee engagement.
- h) Effectively motivating, leading team and retaining high performers.
- i) Utilizing the CRM tool (salesforce.com) to actively manage team's pipeline and productivity measurement.
- j) Delivering on team's scorecard which focuses on new billings and activation of new businesses within predefined segments.
- k) Maintaining a high level of knowledge of GCP products, underwriting requirements and ability to assist team in risk related and day to day operational issues.

American Express International Inc

- a) Global & Regional client management of a \$200M+ portfolio of strategic, high value clients from within the Global Client Group.
- b) Accountable for leading the overall program strategy, focusing on driving program growth, product penetration through the cross-sell of other Global Corporate Payment products and solutions and in understanding and collaborating to deliver against customer goals and objectives.
- c) Responsibility includes leading RFP's, developing and executing the customer strategy, maintaining open channels of communication between the global, regional and local client and account management teams and deepening and expanding business relationships with key decision makers.
- d) Maintain general business knowledge and an awareness of how external factors (Political, Legal, Economic and Technological, Social) will affect client and American Express business and leverage to support and direct client engagement and behavior

# **Regional Relationship Manager & Team Leader DAR**

June 2012 - March 2015

American Express International Inc

- a) Accountable for leading the overall program strategy and execute strategic partnership plans and account reviews that add value to the client's business while ensuring that American Express' revenue and profit objectives are met, with clearly defined outcomes and measurement metrics. Apply consultative selling techniques to direct activities toward a positive outcome.
- b) Expand business relationships with key decision makers, key stakeholders, C level contacts and other influencers, ensuring that we develop and maintain a broad network of sponsors from across the businesses.
- c) Maintain a thorough understanding of competitive landscape with ability to build defensive/offensive strategies.
- d) Proactively provide expertise on policies, bench-marking, and recommendations to optimize programs, reduce costs and drive efficiencies for clients

# **EDUCATION**

# **Masters of Management Studies (MBA)**

August 2001 - April 2003

Mumbai University

#### **Bachelors of Commerce**

June 1998 - April 2001

Mumbai University

# **SKILLS**

# **Organizational**

Get Social Get Healthy - Currently the Network Chair for the committee at American Express Singapore. My primary objective is to build an inclusive and fun environment and bring various LOBs employees together for interaction while promoting healthy lifestyles in and outside of the workplace.

# **LANGUAGES**

	Listening	Reading	Writing	Speaking
English	Native Proficiency	Native Proficiency	Native Proficiency	Native Proficiency

# **OTHER**

# **Additional info**

# Achievements:

- a) Chairman's Award (2016)
- b) GCG Global Mindset Award (2016)
- c) Presidents Club Award (2014)

# Projects:

- a) JAPA Coverage Revamp Project (2016)
- b) JAPA Coverage and Surcharge Committee Core Member (2015)
- c) Partnered with the X-BET Project team (2013) (Cross-Business Engagement Team India) to provide mentoring to an identified "mentee" to support their journey on career and personal development including guidance on driving growth within the portfolio.